PRAVEEN KUMAR REDDY. GANDAVARAPU

p.gandavarapu@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 9652430332

Experience Summary

Having 6 years and 5 Months Experience in Human Resource
Department in Various Companies Like Gayatri sugar complex ltd.,
NELLORE, ANDHRAPRADESH, PVR projects Ltd., PUNE, MAHARASTRA,
INDIA, Albasti and Muktha LLC (ABM), DUBAI, UAE, and Dodla Dairy
Limited., CHITTOOR, ANDHRAPRADESH INDIA.

Professional History

- As a Self Employee In the year of 2012 I started a construction Firm in Tirupati, ANDHRAPRADESH, India. The Firm Name is Pradeepti Infra. Here in this Firm We Mainly concentrate to construct Residential Apartments. Here My Designation is Managing Partner in HR and Administration Department.
- Worked in Dodla Dairy Ltd., Chittoor, Andhrapradesh, India, from April 2010 to June 2011 As a HR Executive
- Worked in Albasti and Muktha LLC (ABM), DUBAI, UAE, from September 2008 to December 2008 as a HR Coordinator.
- Worked in PVR projects Ltd., Pune, Maharastra, INDIA from October 2005 to July 2008 as a Sr. HR Executive.
- Worked in Gayatri Sugar Complex Ltd., Nellore, Andhrapradesh, INDIA
 From January 2002 to March 2004 as a Officer (P&A).

Software Skills

- Having SAP (HR) Knowledge in Enterprise Structure, Organizational Management, Personnel Administration, Payroll, Recruitment and Time Management.
- Working Experience on FoxPro, Microsoft Office, MS Accesses and Windows Operating system.

Achievements

- In the time of Work permits distribution, successfully coordinated with Camp Coordinators, Staff and Employees.
- In the time of WP & RP Renewal, Successfully Coordinated with Various Departments and maintaining the control sheet for Work Permits and Residence Permit.
- Successfully coordinated and assisted all departments for collecting the manpower requirements.
- Handled 300 Work force at M/s Gayatri Sugar Complex Limited., AP
- Canteen, Executive mess and guest house (During off Season) given to contractor and drastically reduced the expenses.

 Mainly Taking Plan Approvals from Concern Authorities, Liaising With All Departments, Looking all Employees Safety, Payroll, and New Employees Recruitment Etc.,

Education

- Completed Master of Business Administration (HRD) from Sri Venkateswara University, Tirupathi, Andhrapradesh in the Year of 2004 (1999-2001).
- Completed Bachelor of Commerce from Sri Venkateswara University, Tirupathi, Andhrapradesh in the Year of 1999 (1996–1999).

EXPERIENCE

Company : Dodla Dairy Ltd., Designation : Executive - HR

Duration : April 2010 to June 2011

Company : Albasti and Muktha LLC.,

Designation : Hr Coordinator

Duration : September 2008 to December 2008

Company : PVR Projects Ltd.,

Duration : October 2005 to July 2008

Designation : Sr. HR Executive

Company : Gayatri Sugar Complex Ltd.,
Duration : January 2002 to March 2004

Designation : Officer (P&A)

DUTIES & RESPONSIBILITIES:

1. Manpower Planning and Recruitment:

- Screening the Manpower and arrange the same according to the need to the departments
- Coordinating Recruitments.

2. Payment of Wages:

- Oversee the end-to-end payroll process,
- Maintain payroll records and systems, including employee data, tax withholding information, and payroll deductions.
- Calculate and process payroll adjustments, such as overtime, bonuses, commissions, and leaves of absence.
- Calculate and process payroll adjustments, such as overtime, bonuses, commissions, and leaves of absence.
- To ensure issue of Pay slips and maintain wage registers.

3. Performance Appraisal:

 Performance appraisal and merit rating scheme, to analyze the training needs of the employees, increment promotion etc.,

4. Disciplinary Action:

 Appropriate Disciplinary action is warranted on erring employees as per the Standing Orders.

5. Attendance System of employees / Leave etc.:

- Late attendance and absenteeism daily report to be circulated to the dept/ section heads Monthly report absenteeism and monitor the Leaves and Lop.
- Deduction of wages for Lop employees though they have adequate leave.

6. Exit interviews:

- Conducting Exit interviews for Resigned Employees and finalized their final account settlements.
- In the time of finalize the Final accounts Calculate Gratuity to eligible employees as per the act.

7. Monitor Statutory Obligations:

- To ensure maintenance of registers and records under various acts and display of exhibits.
- Renewal of factory license
- Canteen facility to the employees including other statutory facilities like Drinking water, Rest Sheds etc.,
- Eligible employee's welfare fund to be send to commissioner of welfare fund annually.
- Handling PF and EPF for the in coming and out going employees, and Preparing PF Annual returns sent to regional Provident fund Inspector.
- Sending Formal notification whenever recruit the candidates.
- Quarterly and Bi Annual Returns sent to Labor Department.

8. Other Administration Responsibilities:

- Maintaining accurate and up-to-date employee records, including personal information, employment contracts, and performance evaluations
- Preparing and processing HR-related documentation, such as employment contracts, offer letters, termination letters, and employment verification letters.
- Creating Annual Holidays.
- All employees and Vehicles movements.
- Other Administrative Responsibilities: Maintenance of Guest House, Company Quarters etc.,

- Submitting new joiners documents in personnel department,
 Maintaining employees WP & RP Expiry data for their renewal date,
- Coordinating with all departments for smooth functioning of the organization.
- o Always maintain excellent rapport with the following statutory areas.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : Praveen Kumar Reddy. Gandavarapu

Contact Number : +91 9652430332

Passport : Valid Up to 29 / November / 2032

Email : <u>p.gandavarapu@gmail.com</u>
Languages known : Telugu, English and Hindi

Nationality : Indian

EDUCATION DETAILS

Highest Level Degree : MBA (Master of Business Administration)

University : Sri venkateswara University

Graduation Period : 1999-2001

EXPERIENCE

HR Experience : 6 Years 5 Months Recent Employer : Pradeepti Infra

Recent Designation : Managing Partner (Administration & HR)

Recent Experience : Around 11 Years